[radio announcer
speaking Spanish]
[child]  What does  sueñito  mean?
[man] Sueñito  ? It means
"little dream."
[waves crashing]
That's it? No story?
Can we go in the water now?
Let him explain.
All right, all right.
Everybody sit down, sit down.
-[children clamoring]
Yes! Yeah!
[all giggling]
All right.
Bueno.
It's the story of a block
that was disappearing.
Once upon a time,
in a far away land called
en un barrio
called Washington Heights.
Say it,
so it doesn't disappear.
[all] Washington Heights!
All right, all right.
Oye, oye, oye.
The streets were made of music.
[tapping out beat]
[over radio] Mi gente!
It's your boy,
It's 5:30 a.m., and here's
today's news.
In a record-breaking heat
wave, the mayor's urging
Limit air conditioner
use, as brownouts
[woman speaking Spanish
over radio]
[Kid Mero]  Check it out,
this weekend's highly
Fiesta in the Heights,
is about to get you out of
your homes and into the
[alarm beeping]
[grunts sleepily]
[sighs heavily]
Hey, Pop.
Best days of my life.
[upbeat music playing]
Bendicion,  Abuela.  Bendicion.
Don't forget to take your
medicine.
-[in Spanish] God bless you.
-[Usnavi] Love you.
[upbeat music continues]
[music stops]
[all laughing]
[record scratching]
[Usnavi rapping] ♪  Lights up
on Washington Heights
-Yo, what are you doing, bro?
-  ♪  I wake up and I got this
♪  I gotta chase away♪
♪  Pop the grate at the crack of
dawn♪
♪  Sing while I wipe down the
awning♪
Hey, y'all. Good morning.
Ice cold  piragua  ,  parcha,
china  , cherry, strawberry and
[both speaking Spanish]
-[rings bell]
-Ice cold  piragua  ,  parcha  ...
[rapping] ♪  I am Usnavi
and you
♪  Reports of my fame are
greatly exaggerated♪
♪  Exacerbated by the fact
That my syntax is highly
♪  'Cuz I emigrated from the
single greatest Little
♪  Dominican Republic
I love it♪
♪  Jesus, I'm jealous of it
And beyond that♪
♪  Ever since my folks passed on
I haven't gone back♪
♪  Goddamn,
I gotta get on that♪
♪  The milk has gone bad♪
♪  Hold up just a second♪
♪  Why is everything in this
fridge warm and tepid?♪
♪  I'd better step it up and
fight the heat♪
♪  'Cuz I'm not makin' any
profit If the coffee
-Yoo-hoo!
-Abuela, my fridge broke.
I got café but no  con leche.
Ay, Dios  . Try my mother's
old recipe.
One can of condensed milk.
Nice.
Oh, hey. Your lottery ticket.
[exclaims]
[rapping] ♪  That was Abuela
She's not really my abuela♪
♪  But she practically
raised me♪
♪  This corner is her escuela♪
♪  Now, you're probably thinkin'
I'm up shit's creek♪
I've never been north
of 96th Street.
♪  Well you must take
the A Train♪
♪  Even farther than Harlem
To northern Manhattan
♪  Get off at 181st and take the
escalator♪
♪  I hope you're writin' this
down I'm gonna test you
♪  I'm getting tested
Times are tough
♪  Two months ago somebody
bought Ortega's♪
♪  Our neighbors started packin'
up and pickin' up♪
♪  And ever since
the rents went up♪
♪  It's gotten mad expensive
But we live with just enough♪
[chorus] ♪  In the Heights♪
♪  I flip the lights and start
my day♪
♪  There are fights
and endless debts♪
♪  And bills to pay♪
♪  In the Heights♪
♪  I can't survive
without café♪
[Usnavi] ♪  I serve café♪
[chorus] ♪  'Cuz tonight
seems like a
♪  En Washington--♪
♪  Next up-- ding!
Kevin Rosario♪
♪  He runs the cab company♪
♪  He struggles in the barrio♪
♪  See, his daughter Nina's off
at college♪
♪  Tuition is mad steep
So he can't sleep♪
♪  Everything he get
is mad cheap♪
♪  Good morning, Usnavi♪
♪  Pan caliente
Café con leche♪
♪  Put 20 dollars on today's
lottery♪
-♪  Okay!
Must be your lucky day♪
♪  Oh, my God,
you're so excited♪
♪  My Nina flew in at 3:00 a.m.
last night♪
♪  Sweet! Abuela's been cooking
all week♪
♪  Compay, when I see you this
weekend...♪
♪  Are we gonna eat!♪
♪  So then Yesenia walks in the
room♪
Aha...
♪  She smells
sex and cheap perfume♪
Oh, no!
♪  It smells like one of those
trees that you hang from
Ay, no!
♪  It's true! She screams,
"Who's in there with you,
Daniela!
♪  Grabs a bat and kicks in the
door♪
Carla!
♪  He's in bed with Jose from
the liquor store!♪
[all]  No me diga!
[Usnavi] And that's Cuca.
The salon ladies.
[all] ♪  Thanks, Usnavi!♪
-[woman] Cuca.
-[purrs]
-[door opening]
-Adios, papi.
-[woman] Bye!
-[door closes]
Sonny, you're late.
Chillax, you know you love me.
[Usnavi rapping]
♪  Me and my cousin runnin'♪
♪  Just another dime-a-dozen
Mom-and-pop stop-and-shop♪
♪  And oh, my God, it's gotten
too darn hot♪
♪  Like my man
Cole Porter said♪
♪  People come through for a few
cold waters♪
♪  And a lottery ticket
Just a part of the routine♪
♪  Everybody's got a job
Everybody's got a dream♪
♪  They gossip, as I sip my
coffee and smirk♪
♪  The first stop as people hop
to work♪
♪  Bust it, I'm like:
"One dollar, two dollars♪
♪  One fifty, one sixty-nine
I got it♪
♪  You want a box of condoms?
What kind?♪
♪  That's two quarters, two
quarter waters
♪  You need a bag for that?
The tax is added"♪
♪  Once you get
some practice at it♪
♪  You do rapid mathematics
automatically♪
♪  Sellin' maxi-pads, fuzzy dice
for taxicabs♪
♪  Practically everybody's
stressed, yes♪
♪  But they press
through the mess♪
♪  Bounce checks and wonder
what's next♪
[chorus] ♪  In the Heights
I buy my coffee and I go♪
♪  I buy my coffee and--♪
♪  Set my sights♪
♪  On only what I need to know♪
♪  What I need to know♪
♪  In the Heights♪
♪  Money is tight, but even so♪
♪  Even so♪
♪  When the lights go down
I blast my radio♪
-♪  You ain't got no skills!♪
-♪  Benny!♪
-♪  Yo, let me get a--♪
-♪  Milky Way♪
-♪  Yeah, and let me
also get a--♪
-♪  And a--♪
-♪  Post♪
-♪  And most important my--♪
-♪  Boss's second coffee♪
-♪  One cream♪
-♪  Five sugars♪
-♪  I'm the number one earner♪
-♪  What?♪
-♪  The fastest learner♪
♪  My boss, he can't keep me
On the damn back burner♪
-♪  Yes he can♪
-♪  I'm makin' moves,
-♪  But guess what?♪
-♪  What?♪
♪  You still ain't
got no skills♪
-♪  Har-de-har♪
-♪  Yo, Vanessa show up yet?♪
-♪  Shut up!♪
-♪  Hey, little homie,
-♪  Man...♪
-♪  Tell Vanessa how you feel♪
♪  Buy the girl a meal
on the real♪
♪  Or you ain't got no skills♪
♪  Nooo!
No, no, nooo!♪
♪  No, no, nooo, no-no-no!
Nooo, no-no-no!♪
♪  No, no-no, no-no, no-no
No-no, no-no, no-no!♪
♪  Mr. Johnson, I got the
security deposit♪
♪  It's locked in a box in the
bottom of my closet♪
♪  It's not reflected in my bank
statement♪
♪  But I've been savin' to make
a down payment
-  ♪  No, no,
I won't let you down♪
[Benny] Yo, here's your chance
Ask her out right now!
♪  I'll see you later
We can look at that lease♪
♪  Bro, do somethin'
Make your move, don't freeze!♪
♪  Hey!♪
♪  You owe me a bottle of cold
champagne!♪
♪  Are you movin'?♪
♪  Just a little credit check
And I'm on that
♪  Well,
your coffee's on the house♪
♪  Okay♪
-♪  Usnavi, ask her out♪
-♪  No way♪
♪  I'll see you later, so...♪
-[door opens, closes]
-[laughing]
Whoa!
♪  Yo, smooth operator
Oh, damn, there she goes♪
♪  Yo, bro, take five
Take a walk outside♪
♪  You look exhausted, lost
Don't let life slide♪
♪  The whole hood is struggling
Times is tight♪
♪  And you're stuck
to this corner
♪  Yeah, I'm a streetlight
Chokin' on the heat♪
♪  The world spins around
While I'm frozen to my seat♪
♪  The people that I know
All keep on rollin' down the
♪  But every day is different
So I'm switchin' up the beat♪
♪  'Cuz my parents came with
nothing
♪  And sure, we're poor
But yo, at least we got the
♪  And it's all about the legacy
They left with me,
♪  And one day
I'll be on a beach with Sonny
[chorus] ♪  In the Heights
I hang my flag up on display♪
[Usnavi] ♪  We came to work
and to live
[chorus] ♪  It reminds me
that I came
[Usnavi] ♪  DR, PR,
we are not stoppin'♪
-[chorus] ♪  In the Heights♪
-♪  Every day, paciencia y fe♪
[Usnavi] ♪  Until the day
we go from
[chorus] ♪  In the Heights
I've got today♪
♪  Today's all we got,
so we cannot stop♪
♪  This is our block♪
[chorus] ♪  In the Heights
I hang my flag up on display♪
♪ It reminds me that I came
from miles away my family
♪  In the Heights
It gets more expensive
♪  Every day♪
♪  And tonight is so far away♪
♪  But as for mañana, mi pana
Ya gotta just keep watchin'♪
-  ♪  You'll see
the late nights♪
♪  You'll taste beans and rice♪
-  ♪  The syrup and shaved ice♪
-  ♪  In the Heights♪
♪  I ain't gonna say it twice♪
-  ♪  Turn up the streetlights♪
-  ♪  In the Heights♪
♪  We're takin' a flight♪
♪  To a couple of days in the
life of what it's like♪
♪  En Washington Heights!♪
[indistinct chatter]
[Usnavi] Come on,
stack that right there,
Let's just keep those boxes in
order, too.
Ah. the hustle never ends.
-Alejandro, how you doing?
-  [speaking Spanish]
-[in English]
How's the law office?
-You're spitting image of your
old man.
-[Alejandro laughs]
-Yeah, so how was the DR?
I got to visit
some old friends.
I wish I could go back more
often.
That's facts.
-Hey, so you get to check out
my dad's old place?
Same story as last time?
You ready?
[speaks Spanish]
-Don't play!
-[chuckles]
Now, it's probably not how you
remember it,
but it could be an opportunity
to bring it back to life.
[Usnavi speaking Spanish]
My pops would be rolling in his
grave if he saw what came
[Alejandro]
The electricity's shot.
Half the roof got taken in the
hurricane.
Thus the low asking price,
the quick sale.
[Usnavi]  "El Sueñito."
Pop's little dream.
Yo, I remember, man, when--
I used to be working
in the back
And I was like John Wick.
I'd be like...
-  [speaking Spanish]
-  [chuckles]
I've been saving up all my
pennies in my piggy bank for
Yeah, on these blocks,
you can't walk two steps
without bumping into someone's
big plans.
Mijo...
[speaking Spanish]
[soft guitar music playing]
[chuckles softly]
[in English] Okay, I'm in.
Thank you, man.
I'll see you,  papa.
-[speaking Spanish]
-[in English] Come on.
Here we go. [chuckles]
This is crazy!
Let's go!
Mine was a... quaint little
sueñito.
If I made it back to the
Dominican Republic, then we
But Nina Rosario's dreams were
all about reach.
Spelling bee champ,
valedictorian,
managed her dad's business
and basically...
she was like a little sister
to me.
Girl was a rocket, determined
to go far.
What?
The genius is back!
-I missed you!
-Me, too. Did you just get in?
Yeah, late last night.
-Final week?
-Yeah, it's really happening.
Yo, so much to catch up on.
-Come over for a free
mani-pedi, yeah?
Mm-hm. Oh, and Benny's on the
dispatch today. Just sayin'.
♪  Check one, two, three♪
♪  This is Benny on the dispatch
Yo♪
♪  Atención, yo, attention♪
♪  It's Benny, and I'd like to
mention♪
♪  I'm on the microphone this
mornin'♪
♪  Honk your horn
if you want it♪
♪  Okay, we got traffic on the
West Side♪
♪  Get off at 79, and take the
left side♪
♪  Of Riverside Drive, you might
slide♪
♪  West End's your best friend
If you catch the lights♪
♪  And don't take the Deegan♪
♪  Yo, Big Papi is in town this
weekend♪
♪  Sorry Dominicans,
take Route 87♪
♪  You ain't getting
back in again♪
♪  Hold up a minute♪
-♪  Benny, hey♪
-♪  Nina, you're home today♪
-♪  Any sign?♪
-♪  Of your dad,
-♪  Anyway♪
-♪  It's good to see
-♪  Anytime♪
-♪  Hold up a minute, or wait♪
♪  You used to run this
dispatch, right?♪
♪  Once or twice♪
♪  Okay, well,
check the technique♪
♪  Yo! There's a
traffic accident
♪ At the intersection of 10th
Ave and the Jacob Javitz
♪  And check it,
don't get stuck in
♪  There's a double-decker bus
wreck♪
♪  Now listen up, we got a
special guest♪
-♪  Live and direct from a year
out west♪
-♪  Welcome her back, 'cause she
looks mad stressed!♪
♪  Nina Rosario,
the barrio's best♪
-[horns honking]
-♪  Whoo! Honk your horns♪
-No, no, no, no...
-Go, go, go.
♪  She's smiling♪
♪  Say hello♪
♪  Hello♪
-Whoo!
-♪  Good morning♪
♪  I ought to let you work♪
♪  Thanks for the
welcome wagon♪
♪  Anytime♪
♪  Anytime, Nina♪
♪  Stay here with me♪
♪  It's getting hot outside♪
♪  Turn up the AC♪
♪  Stay here with me♪
You thirsty as hell.
[woman 1] Ohh!
You used to date?
[woman 2] No way,
the boss's daughter?
Nina Rosario!
-Oh! Yo!
-What's up?
-[siren beeps]
-Yo, hold up.
Don't get hit by a car, girl,
you just got here.
Oh, man.
[Usnavi] Yo, mad changes
happening on the block since
Oh, yeah. I mean,
at least your dad
Yo, the cleaners next door,
nine dollars a shirt.
-What?
-Yo! Look who's home!
Look at you!
Why are you taller than me?
I know, my man grew a couple
inches, he think he a man.
-[scoffs] Man, shut up.
-I see you.
Listen, you down to march next
week?
Like we used to?
What's the cause?
They're talking about kicking
out all the DREAMers.
It's time to make some noise.
You want to come?
[Abuela Claudia]
I know that voice!
Woo-hoo! [speaking Spanish]
-[in English] Count me in.
-Yo. Later.
-Well, you do good? You done?
-Yeah.
-My man, who's watching the
store?
-Yo!
-Shit!
Pete! You can't just take that!
Bro! Get back here, man!
That's on your tab, bro!
Both of y'all.
[Nina whispering] Oh, yes.
Hand-embroidered
by your mother.
May she rest in peace.
We'll use them for the party.
They're beautiful.
[Usnavi]
Abuela Claudia never had kids,
so she adopted the whole
block as her own.
Adopted our  sueñitos  , too.
[speaking Spanish]
[in English]
When I got to Stanford...
...the isolation, Abuela.
The loneliness.
I was, like, "What am I doing
here?"
[speaking Spanish]
[in English]  Mira  , when
my  mamá  came from Cuba...
Ay,  Dios mío.
She felt like one tiny grain of
sand from the beaches we left
What did she do?
She bought a winter coat
and a pair of velvet gloves.
Her hands were cracked
from the cleaning fluids.
But the gloves hid that.
We had to assert our dignity in
small ways.
That's why these napkins are
beautiful.
That's why my mother's gloves
were beautiful.
Little details that tell the
world, we are not invisible.
[speaking Spanish]
[man singing in Spanish]
♪  Respira♪
-♪  Breathe♪
-[men singing in Spanish]
♪  Respira♪
♪  This is my street♪
♪  I smile at the faces♪
-  ♪  I've known all my life♪
-Hey, Nina.  Como estás?
♪  They regard me with pride♪
♪  And everyone's sweet♪
♪  They say,
"You're going places"♪
♪  So how can I say
that while I was away♪
-♪  I had so much to hide?♪
-Hey, Nina!
♪  Hey, guys, it's me♪
♪  The biggest disappointment
you know♪
♪  The kid couldn't hack it♪
♪  She's back and she's walkin'
real slow♪
-♪  Welcome home♪
-♪  Just breathe♪
[chorus]  ♪ Sigué andando
el camino por
♪  Respira♪
-♪  Just breathe♪
-[chorus] ♪  Y si pierdes mis♪
♪  huellas,
que Dios te bendiga♪
-♪ Respira ♪
-♪ As the radio plays ♪
♪  Old forgotten boleros♪
♪  I think of the days when this
city was mine♪
♪  I remember the praise♪
-  ♪  "Ay, te adoro, te quiero"♪
-  [chorus] ♪  Te adoro♪
♪  The neighborhood waved
and said♪
-  ♪  "Nina, be brave and you're
gonna be fine"♪
♪  And maybe it's me♪
-  ♪  But it all seems like
lifetimes ago♪
♪  So what do I say
to these faces
♪  "Hey, I'm home?"♪
♪  Mira, Nina♪
-♪  Hey...♪
-♪  No me preocupo por ella♪
♪  They're not worried
about me♪
♪  Mira, alli está
nuestra estrella♪
♪  They are all counting on me
to succeed♪
♪  Ella si da la talla♪
♪  I am the one
who made it out!♪
♪  The one who always made the
grade♪
-  ♪  But maybe I should have
just stayed home♪
♪  When I was a child, I stayed
wide awake♪
♪  Climbed to
the highest place♪
♪  On every fire escape♪
-♪  Restless to climb♪
-♪  Respira♪
♪  I got every scholarship♪
♪  Saved every dollar♪
♪  The first to go to college♪
-♪  How do I tell them why♪
-♪  Respira♪
♪  I'm coming back home?♪
♪  With my eyes on the horizon♪
♪  Just me and GWB♪
♪  Asking, "Gee, Nina♪
♪  What am I gonna be?"♪
♪  Straighten the spine♪
♪  Smile for the neighbors♪
♪  Everything's fine♪
♪  Everything's cool♪
♪  The standard reply♪
♪  Lots of tests,
lots of papers♪
♪  Smile, wave goodbye♪
♪  And pray to the sky,
oh, God♪
-♪  And how do I dare to say?♪
-♪  Nina♪
-♪  Can I go in there and say♪
♪  I know that I'm
letting you down♪
Nina!
♪  Just...♪
♪  Breathe♪
[Nina]  The reality of an elite
school...
it's no joke, Pop.
Yeah, when I left, y'all were,
like,
"It's gonna be great. Go show
'em who we are. Go represent."
The truth is...
is that most of the time I'm
at Stanford feels like a
De verdad?  Of who?
Of my family.
My community.
Like the dean, he invited me
to this diversity dinner.
Super-wealthy donors, trustees,
the whole nine.
And I wore this black cocktail
dress and I was walking to my
and one of the patrons shoved
her plate into my arms
and said, "I ordered the
vegetarian option."
-No.
-Yeah.
And all the servers,
all Latino,
like, "Ooh, what's this
trigueña  gonna do?"
"Ooh, what's she gon' do?
Is she with us?
Ah, bueno.  There's no
shame in waiting tables.
And there's no shame
in having a different path.
Like you.
Dad... the deadline passed.
The extension
on spring tuition.
[speaking Spanish]
-[in English] Yeah.
-But I didn't receive notice.
Yeah, they let me finish off my
classes, but we owe them.
No, don't you give it a second
thought. I'm on it. Hm?
Dad...
The deadline to pay and enroll
for next semester also passed.
[speaking Spanish]
[in English] How come you know
about all this
I switched the info.
I gave the finance office
Well, why would you do that?
Because you sold half the
business, and it barely covered
I don't want you doing
something
-  Espera  , that sale pulled
us out of debt.
You and I both know that
finances were tenuous before
And this might not be feasible.
-I'm gonna call them right now.
-Dad, Stanford's over.
Stop overreacting,
Nina, please.
-Dad, I'm serious.
-Oye!
You don't tell me how much we
can afford.
You're not the parent. Hm?
God bless you.  Dios te bendiga.
[man]  Gracias!
[Abuela Claudia
speaking Spanish]
What's all over those pipes?
-Rust.
-Rust?
Lovely.
-[speaking Spanish]
-[in English] That's the roof.
On the floor?
Ay, Usnavi.
Tu eres un  workaholic.
You think it will be different
in the Dominican Republic?
Just like my  mamá.
Morning and night, year after
year... to what end?
To wake up and scrub another
floor till the day she died.
Yeah, but... here I work to
survive.
El Sueñito  will be a
labor of love.
The  bodega  was only supposed
to be temporary,
but now... I'm like, almost 30.
The plan was always to go back.
Hopefully, I won't be going
alone.
You, me and Sonny?
Y Sonny?  Is he on board?
He's my next ask.
I'm not going without him.
Look, I got Sonny.
You know I can't go nowhere
without you.
I took care of my community,
no?
-Hell, yes!
-[chuckles]
El Sueñito  2.0.
The tropical air'll keep you
young, girl!
Caramba  , buy me a bikini!
[laughs] Let's go!
[rap music playing]
[Sonny] I don't know, man.
Leave Washington Heights?
I'd have to talk to my dad...
[Usnavi] You're just a kid.
You don't even know. For real.
Dominican Republic's gonna blow
your mind.
Look...
You do you. It's all good. But
don't be roping me into your
Yo... [exhales]
Beach.
Merengue  .  Carnaval.
Summer all year 'round.
Who's gonna greet you in DR?
Some cousin you saw two
Christmases ago?
Best days of my life
were there.
[laughs]
That's the corniest thing I've
ever heard.
You came here when you was
eight.
You got... "island memories."
Not me. I was in Pampers
on that plane.
NYC's my spot.
I got my island, okay?
Go get yours.
Don't forget how you got your
name.
-Yo...
-Just, fix the fridge.
Yeah, all right.
Bro, you think you're funny?
What's "Usnavi" mean, anyway?
That sounds weird.
No, it doesn't.
-All right. All right, all
right, all right.
On my dad's first trip to
Nueva York...
he saw a passing ship on
the horizon.
And... he was, like, "Wow,
that's gonna be
-Usnavi!
-[all] Ohh...
Usnavi...
I like it.
Thank you.
[hold music playing over phone]
-[woman]  Hi, Mr. Rosario?
-Yes, yes, I'm here.
Yes, I'm not sure the
information you received
In actuality, we're still
accepting tuition
So the deadline hasn't passed?
No, it has not passed.
Would you like to know the
Yes. I have a pencil.
Sure, the balance that's due
for the fall semester...
[Usnavi]  Now, remember,
the block was
Exhibit A: Daniela's salon.
Moving in a week, after
decades of makeovers,
the skin-deep kind
and the emotional kind.
No one could fill her shoes.
Literally, they were like
four inches high.
He doesn't have an apartment.
He doesn't pay rent anywhere.
He's bouncing between
two girls' houses.
-Of course he is.
-Mm-hm. Mm-hm. Mm-hm.
You know what?
It's mad we allow
-We need to have a better
standard.
Tres paradas...
pickety, packety, poom,
-.and you're at the new spot.
-  [speaking Spanish]
[in English] I'm too old,
and the Bronx is
Que voy a hacer?
I was priced out.
[speaking Spanish]
Most of my clients already up
and moved to the Grand
Hey, built in customers.
My lunch break
isn't long enough
[scoffs] Jessica...
One: swipe the fare card.
Two: ride three stops.
Three: arrive at my new
location.
Ten minutes max.
Ten minutes?  Cariño.
What are you riding, a time
machine?
Excuse me?
No, she didn't, right?
-Our people survived
slave ships.
-We survived  Taino  genocide.
-[women agreeing]
-We survived  conquistadores
and dictators.
You're telling me we can't
survive the D Train to the
[women laughing]
-  [speaking Spanish]
-[in English] Okay, okay, okay.
And who cuts your hair better
than me?
[clamoring]
-[door opening]
-Hello, hello...
For you,  mamita  , front of
the line!  Oye!
-Emergency, coming through!
-[all exclaiming]
Mira, Nina!
-♪  Gorgeous!♪
-♪  Linda!♪
♪  Tell me something
I don't know♪
-♪  Vieja!♪
-♪  Sucia!♪
-♪  Cabrona!♪
-♪  Tell me something
-♪  A little off the top♪
-♪  A little on the side♪
♪  A little bit of news you
heard around the barrio♪
♪  Tell me something
I don't know♪
♪  Bueno
You didn't hear this from me♪
♪  But some
little birdie told me♪
♪  Usnavi had sex with Yolanda♪
♪  No me diga!♪
♪  Ay, no!♪
♪  He'd never go out with a
skank like that♪
-  ♪  Please tell me
you're joking♪
♪  Just wanted to see what you'd
say♪
♪  Tell me something
I don't know♪
-  ♪  Mmm-hmm-mmm♪
-What? I don't care!
♪  Ay, bendito!♪
♪  So, Nina♪
♪  I hear you been
talking to Benny♪
-♪  And what do you hear?♪
-♪  I hear plenty♪
♪  They say he's got quite a
big... taxi!♪
-♪  No me diga!♪
-♪  Okay♪
♪  I don't wanna know where you
heard all that♪
♪  I don't think I know what you
mean♪
♪  Carla, he's packing a stretch
limousine♪
♪  Tell me something
I don't know♪
♪  Long as he keeps it clean♪
Oh, God.
♪  Ay, Dios mío!♪
♪  Nina, seriously, we knew
you'd be♪
♪  The one to make it out♪
♪  I'll bet you impressed them
all out west♪
-  ♪  You were always the best,
no doubt♪
♪  We want front row seats to
your graduation♪
-♪  They'll call your name♪
-♪  And we'll scream and shout♪
You guys!
[music stops]
I... dropped out.
[all]  No me diga.
Yeah. I should go.
-[door closes]
-Well, that's a shitty
She probably flunked out.
Or she got a little bun in the
oven, you know?
What the hell happened?
♪  I don't know♪
♪  Tell me something
I don't know♪
♪  Que se yo?♪
[music stops]
Dani, I'm taking lunch.
Go get me a soda, please?
-[Vanessa] Yeah.
-Where's she sneaking off to?
That was real quick.
Okay, so we're gonna shave the
whole thing.
Vanessa.
[speaking Spanish]
-Vanessa!
-[whistles]
[Usnavi]  Vanessa,
tough as nails.
Dreamed of being a downtown
fashion designer.
To her, a  sueñito  was something
you keep a secret.
♪  The elevated train
by my window
♪  The rattling screams
Don't disrupt my dreams♪
♪  It's a lullaby in its way♪
♪  The elevated train drives
everyone insane♪
♪  But I don't mind, oh, no♪
♪  When I bring back boys
They can't tolerate the noise♪
♪  And that's okay
'Cuz I never let them stay♪
♪  And one day
I'm hoppin' that
♪  And I'm riding away♪
♪  It won't be long now♪
♪  The boys around the way
holler at me♪
♪  When I'm walking
down the street♪
♪  Their machismo pride
Doesn't break my stride♪
Hey, good morning to you, too,
sweetheart.
♪  It's a compliment,
so they say♪
♪  The boys around the way
Holler at me every day♪
♪  But I don't mind,
oh, no, no♪
♪  If I'm in the mood
It will not be with some dude♪
♪  Who is whistling
'Cuz he has nothing to say♪
♪  Or who's honking at me from a
Chevrolet♪
♪  One day
I'm hoppin' in a limousine♪
♪  And I'm driving away♪
♪  Yeah, yeah, yeah♪
♪  It won't be long now♪
[cell phone ringing]
[Vanessa]  I'm sorry.
Had to rush to get
I e-mailed you a few days ago,
but I brought an extra copy.
Here, just in case.
Sorry, here.
Ah, Miss Morales.
-Yeah-- yes.
-Right.
I'm sorry, honey. I meant to
call you.
Oh... Uh, I got bank checks.
First month, last month and
security. Good as cash.
It's just without a solid
credit check, there's not much
Maybe your parents could
co-sign.
Assuming they can prove income
40 times the rent.
You know what? Get it to me by
five. I'll see what I can do.
-Hi!
-Hi.
-So glad you could make it.
-So good to see you.
-Thanks for having us.
-Good to meet you, yeah.
[rental agent]
These are the windows I was
[woman] Oh, fabulous.
Absolutely gorgeous.
[door opens, closes]
Yo, how'd it go?
Are we popping champagne?
The realtor took one look at
this, and was, like... "No."
Well, nope on her.
There's something
on your shirt.
[groans]
Just this.
[cash register dings]
My cousin over there,
with his tongue hanging out...
has been meaning to ask...
Yeah?
What a lady like yourself...
would be doing this weekend.
Does your cousin dance?
Like a drunk Chita Rivera.
Stop.
Tell your cousin...
Fiesta in the Heights.
We can hit a few clubs.
Check out the fireworks.
Keep it.
-Thanks.
-Have a good day.
[door opens, closes]
♪  Oh snap! Who's that?♪
♪  Don't touch me, I'm too hot!
Yes!♪
♪  Que paso? Here I go♪
♪  So dope! Y tu lo sabes♪
-♪  No paré♪
-♪  Sigué, sigué♪
♪  Did you see me?
Freaky, freaky♪
♪  What a way to begin
the weekend♪
♪  Sonny, anything you want is
free, man♪
♪  And my dearly beloved
Dominican Republic♪
-♪  I haven't forgotten you♪
-♪  You♪
♪  Gonna see this honey
Gon' make a little money♪
-♪  And one day I'll hop
Jet Blue♪
♪  But until that fateful day
I'm grateful
♪  I'm running to make it home♪
♪  And home's where
Vanessa's running away from♪
♪  I'm running to make it home♪
♪  And home's where
Vanessa's running away from♪
♪  The neighborhood salon is the
place I am working for
♪  As I cut their hair
Ladies talk and share♪
♪  Every day
Who's doin' who and why♪
♪  The neighborhood salon
doesn't pay me What I
♪  But I don't mind♪
♪  As I sweep the curb♪
♪  I can hear those
turbo engines♪
♪  Blazing a trail
through the sky♪
♪  I look up and think about the
years gone by♪
♪  One day I'm walkin' to JFK♪
♪  And I'm gonna fly♪
♪  It won't be long now♪
♪  Any day♪
Girl, what the hell?
Look what you did.
Yes, that's my hair, girl.
What you gonna do about it?
And in the middle!
You got me walking around here
looking like a cockatoo!
-[cockatoo sqwauks]
-[boy] Chita Rivera?
Who's that?
Banana hat lady?
No, that's Carmen Miranda.
Unibrow artist lady?
-What? No.
-[girl] Shut up!
What did they teach you
for Hispanic Heritage Month?
Listen, and repeat after me.
Chita, Rita, Frida,
Celia, Dolores, Isabel,
Sandra, Julia, Rigoberta,
Mirabal.
-Ready?
-[all] Yes!
-Go.
-[all] Chita, Rita, Frida,
Celia, Dolores...
Isabel, Sandra, Julia...
Rigoberta, Mirabal.
[speaking Spanish]
[in English] Plus, Sonia.
Supreme Court Justice.
Come on! Let's go.
Thank you.
Yo, you all still open, man?
Everybody closed early
-We headed to the pool.
-Let's go.
There is a god!
Yo, don't take nothing from
there without my permission.
Yo, come on, let's roll, man.
[Usnavi] All right, all right.
-Yo, Sonny, come on.
-Yeah, I'm coming!
-[phone ringing]
-[Usnavi] Yo, answer that.
Hello?
Holy shit!
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Yo, why these  chancletas
make my toes wrinkle?
Move, come on.
-It's like they're squeezing my
joints together.
Phone call! Lotto office.
-What, are these Lotto numbers?
-We sold-- a winner.
-Yesterday.
-What?
Oh, shit, I played, bro.
Yo, let's talk profit sharing.
-I want a cut of your cut.
-Yeah, my cut is zero.
-Man.
-What's the payout?
And don't tell me no $500. I
spent a lot of money on these
♪  Ninety-six thousand♪
♪  Damn♪
♪  Dollars? Holla!♪
♪  Ninety-six thousand♪
♪  That's a lot of spray cans♪
♪  Yo, if I won
the Lotto tomorrow♪
♪  Well, I know I
wouldn't bother goin' on no
♪  I pick a business school
And pay the entrance fee♪
♪  And maybe if you're lucky
You'll stay friends with me♪
♪  I'll be a businessman
Richer than Nina's daddy♪
♪  Tiger Woods and I on
the links
♪  My money's makin' money
I'm goin' from
♪  Keep the bling I want
the brass ring, like Frodo♪
♪  Oh, no, here goes
Mr. Braggadocio♪
♪  Next thing you know
You lying like Pinocchio♪
♪  If you're scared of the bull
Stay out the rodeo♪
♪  Yo, I got more flows than
Obi-Wan Kenobi, oh♪
♪  Oh, you better stop rappin'
You not ready♪
♪  It's gonna get hot and heavy
And you already sweaty♪
-♪  Yo-yo-yo!♪
-♪  Yo, yo! I'm sorry was
♪  Shut up, go home
And pull your damn pants up♪
-♪  As for you, Mr. Frodo
of the Shire♪
♪  96 G's ain't enough to
retire-- C'mon!♪
♪  I'll have enough to knock
your ass Off its axis♪
♪  You'll have a knapsack full
of jack after taxes♪
-♪  Ninety-six thousand♪
-♪  Ay, alabanza!♪
-♪  No me diga!♪
-♪  Ninety-six thousand♪
-  ♪  I never win shit♪
♪  Ninety-six thousand!♪
♪  For real, though♪
♪  Imagine how it would feel
goin' real slow♪
♪  Down the highway of life with
no regrets♪
♪  And no breakin' your neck
For respect or a paycheck♪
♪  For real, though♪
♪  I'll take a break
from the wheel
♪  The biggest block party
Everybody here♪
♪  A weekend when we can breathe
Take it easy♪
♪  Yo! Ma, it's me,
check my ticket♪
♪  Check one, two, three♪
-♪  What would you do with
ninety-six G's?♪
♪  I mean, if it's just between
you and me♪
♪  Esa pregunta es tricky♪
♪  I know♪
♪  With 96 G's♪
♪  I'd start my life with a
brand new lease♪
♪  Atlantic City with a
Malibu Breeze♪
♪  And a brand new weave♪
♪  Ay, maybe just bleach♪
♪  Y'all are freaks♪
-  ♪  Yo, I'm just sayin'♪
-Look at her.
♪  It's silly when we get
Into these
♪  You really want some
bread? Then go ahead,
♪  And cross them off the list
as you pursue 'em♪
♪  And with those 96
I know precisely
-♪  What you doing?
-  What am I doing?
♪  It takes half of that
cash Just to save my ass
♪  Sonny can keep the coffee
brewin'♪
♪  I'll spend a few on you♪
♪  'Cuz the only room
with a view
♪  And I could give
Abuela Claudia
♪  Just fly me down
to Puerto Plata
-♪  You really love
this business?♪
♪  Tough, Merry Christmas♪
♪  You're now
the youngest tycoon
♪  Yo, with 96,000
I'd finally fix housing♪
♪  Give the barrio computers
And wireless web browsing♪
♪  Your kids are living without
A good edumacation♪
♪  Change the station
Teach 'em
-♪  The rent is escalatin'♪
-♪  What?♪
-♪  The rich are penetratin'♪
♪  We pay our corporations
When we should be
-♪  What?♪
-♪  What about immigration?♪
-♪  Politicians be hatin'♪
-♪  What?♪
-♪  Racism in this nation's♪
♪  Gone from latent to blatant♪
♪  I'll cash my ticket
and picket
♪  Never lose my focus
'Til the city takes notice♪
♪  And you know this, man!
I'll never sleep♪
♪  Because the ghetto has a
million promises For me
You are so cute.
I was just thinking off the top
of my head.
-What's your name?
-Jen.
♪  Ninety-six K... Go♪
♪  If I win the lottery♪
♪  You'll never see me again♪
♪  Damn, we only jokin'
Stay broke, then♪
♪  I'll be downtown♪
♪  Get a nice studio♪
♪  Get out of the barrio♪
-♪  For real, though, imagine
how it would feel♪
-♪  Goin' real slow, down the
highway of life♪
♪  With no regrets, and no
breakin' your neck♪
♪  You'll wonder
where I've been♪
♪  For respect or a paycheck♪
-♪  Ninety-six thousand♪
-♪  It's silly when we get♪
♪  Into these crazy
hypotheticals♪
♪  'll take a break
from the wheel♪
-♪  Ninety-six thousand♪
-♪  And we'll throw the biggest
-♪  Everybody here♪
-♪  Ninety-six thousand!♪
-♪  I'll see you around♪
-♪  And with those 96 I know
-♪  Check one, two, three♪
-♪  And with the dolla, dolla♪
-♪  Ninety-six G's♪
-♪  We get to holla, holla♪
-♪  Between you and me♪
-♪  We rock the hot Impala♪
-  ♪  And no breakin' your neck
for respect...♪
-♪  Ninety-six G's♪
-  ♪  I'll be downtown♪
-  ♪  A brand new lease♪
-  ♪  We rock beyond mañana♪
-♪  A Malibu Breeze♪
-  ♪  See you around!♪
♪  A weekend when we can breathe
Take it easy♪
♪  Around♪
-  ♪  Whoa-oh-oh!♪
-  ♪  Whoa!♪
-  ♪  Yeah♪
-  ♪  Whoa-oh-oh! Whoa-oh-oh!♪
-  ♪  I'll be downtown♪
-  ♪  We could pay off the debts
-  ♪  We could tell
everyone we know♪
♪  I could get on a plane
and go♪
♪  We be swimmin' in dough, yo♪
♪  No tip-toeing
We'll get the dough and♪
♪  Once we get going
We're never gonna♪
♪  Stop tip-toeing
We'll get the dough and♪
♪  Once we get going
We're never gonna♪
-♪  Ninety-six thousand♪
-♪  No tip-toeing♪
-  ♪  We'll get the dough and♪
♪  Ninety-six thousand♪
-  ♪  Once we get going♪
-We got the numbers, let's go!
♪  Ninety-six thousand♪
-Five!
-  ♪  Ninety-six thousand♪
-Seven!
-Sixteen!
-  ♪  Ninety-six thousand♪
-Twenty-six!
-♪  Ninety-six thousand♪
-♪  We'll get the dough and♪
♪  Once we get goin'
We're never gonna♪
-  ♪  Stop!♪
-Thirty-three!
[disappointed clamor]
-Nobody?
-You put in ten dollars?
Oh, shit. This is the one.
Oh, man.
[groaning]
This is it! This is it!
[exclaiming then
disappointed groan]
So who won?
That's what everyone was
wondering.
But the ticket was never turned
in.
What? Now you talking crazy,
boy.
-Yo, you lying. Tell us, man.
-Yeah, tell us.
If I knew, I would.
The point is not who won...
but that we all had a  sueñito.
And when it comes to dreams...
we had to keep scraping by.
♪  Oh, que calor, que calor♪
♪  Que calor, que calor♪
♪  Oh, piragua, piragua♪
♪  New block of ice, piragua♪
♪  Piragua, piragua♪
♪  So sweet and nice, piragua♪
♪  Tengo de mango,
tengo de parcha♪
♪  De pina y de fresa♪
♪  Tengo de china, de limón♪
♪  De peso y de peseta, hey!♪
♪  Piragua, piragua♪
♪  New block of ice, piragua♪
♪  So sweet and nice, piragua♪
♪  It's hotter than the islands
are today♪
♪  And Mister Softee's trying to
shut me down♪
♪  But I keep scraping by till I
can say♪
♪  Hey, pana, I run this town!♪
♪  Piragua, piragua♪
-You hit my truck?
-  ♪  Keep scraping by, piragua♪
-Get out of here!
This is my block.
♪  Keep scraping by, piragua♪
♪  Keep scraping by, keep
scraping by♪
♪  Lai, lo, le, lo, lai!
Lai, lo, le, lo, lai!♪
♪  Keep scraping by,
keep scraping by♪
♪  Lo, le, lo, lai!
Keep scraping by♪
♪  Oh, que calor, que calor♪
♪  Que calor, que calor,
que calor♪
Punk!
Stitchwork like this doesn't
exist anymore.
Mm-hm.
Handmade by an old friend.
How much will you take for 'em?
[laughing]
Oh, no, no. Not for sale.
They're for a special occasion
this weekend.
-Does tomorrow by 4:00 work?
-Oh, perfect!
-  Gracias.
-All right,
Plus tax. I'll waive the rush
fee.
Cash or credit?
Bueno.
-Let me think about it.
-Of course.
Welcome to the block.
Admit it.
You're happy
I didn't make it at
I mean, Nina,
I'm not gonna lie.
This feels great.
Girl gets into NYU, she gets
into Columbia...
-but she had to go to the
farthest place.
Nina, I'm not gonna be a ball
and chain.
Right, I told you--
We talked ab--
-Here we go.
-What do you mean,
Shh. Let me just listen to my
block.
-[inhales]
-[distant city sounds]
♪  I used to think♪
♪  We lived at the
top of the world♪
♪  When the world was just
a subway map♪
♪  And the One-slash-Nine♪
♪  Climbed a dotted line
to my place♪
♪  There's no Nine train now♪
Right.
♪  I used to think♪
♪  The Bronx was a place
in the sky♪
♪  When the world was just a
subway map♪
♪  And my thoughts took shape♪
♪  On that fire escape♪
♪  Can you remind me♪
♪  Of what it was like♪
♪  At the top of the world?♪
♪  Come with me♪
Oh, no.
♪  We begin July with a stop
At my corner fire hydrant♪
♪  You would open it
every summer♪
♪  I would bust it with a wrench
Till my face got drenched♪
-  ♪  Till I heard the sirens♪
-Yep.
-♪  And then I ran like hell♪
-♪  You ran like hell♪
-♪  Yeah, I ran like hell♪
-♪  I remember well♪
♪  To your father's
dispatch window♪
♪  "Hey, let me in, yo
They're coming to get me!"♪
♪  You were always in constant
trouble♪
No, I wasn't.
♪  Then your dad would act all
snide But he'd let me
♪  You'd be there inside♪
♪  Life was easier then♪
♪  Nina, everything is easier
When you're home♪
♪  The street's a little kinder
♪  Can't you see that the day
seems clearer♪
♪  Now that you are here or is
it me?♪
♪  Maybe it's just me♪
♪  We gotta go
I wanna show you all I know♪
♪  The sun is setting
And the light is getting low♪
♪  Are we going
to Castle Garden?♪
♪  Maybe, maybe not, but way to
take a shot When the day
♪  I got a perfect shady spot
A little ways away♪
-♪  That oughta cool us down♪
-♪  Cool us down♪
-♪  Welcome back to town♪
-♪  Hey!♪
♪  Now, back in high school when
it darkened You'd hang
♪  And Usnavi
would bring his radio♪
♪  As I walked home
from Senior Studies♪
♪  I'd see you rapping with your
buddies♪
-♪  With the volume high♪
-♪  I walked on by♪
♪  You walked on by♪
♪ No paré! Sigué, sigué! ♪
-Get in here, girl!
-No...
Come on!
♪ No paré! Sigué, sigué! ♪
♪  No paré! Sigué, sigué!
No paré! Sigué, sigué!♪
No paré! Sigué!♪
♪  When you're home♪
♪  The summer nights are cooler
When you're home♪
♪  Now that you're
here with me♪
♪  And that song
you are hearing♪
♪  Is the neighborhood just
cheering you along♪
-♪  Don't say that♪
-♪  What's wrong?♪
♪  Don't say that!♪
♪  When I was younger
I'd imagine what would happen♪
♪  If my parents had stayed in
Puerto Rico♪
♪  Who would I be
If I had never seen Manhattan♪
♪  If I lived in Puerto Rico
with my people♪
♪  My people♪
♪  I feel like all my life
I've tried to find the answer♪
♪  Working harder,
learning Spanish♪
♪  Learning all I can♪
♪  I thought I might find the
answer out at
♪  But I'd stare out
at the sea♪
♪  Thinking, where am I supposed
to be?♪
♪  So please don't say you're
proud of me♪
♪  When I've lost my way♪
♪  Then can I say♪
♪  I couldn't get my mind off
you all day♪
♪  Now, listen to me
That may be how
♪  But Nina please believe
That when you find your way
♪  You are gonna change the
world and then We're all
♪  We knew her when♪
♪  Yeah♪
-♪  This was your home♪
-♪  I'm home♪
-  ♪  Welcome home♪
-  ♪  When you're here with me♪
-♪  Welcome home♪
-♪  I used to think we lived♪
-♪  At the top of the world♪
-♪  Welcome home♪
♪  You're finally home♪
I'm home.
Hey, boss, I got your caffeine.
I'm in a meeting.
Oh, hey, Pike.
[phone ringing]
Everything okay?
Thank you, Benny.
Thank you very much.
-Need anything else?
-No, no. We're good,
If you need--
Café con leche.
Number twelve...
[Usnavi]  It's better
than his current
I can pay for his flights, to
and from.
Christmas, summers...
Just so that he doesn't go too
long without seeing you.
And, you know, I know
you're his dad,
and I'm just his big cousin,
but...
I mean...
this could be good for
[chatter on television]
You're unsure.
Talk to me.
Chill out. You're hovering.
You're doing that thing, you
should...
That's your first of the day?
Listen, if I could be like...
"Out you go, Sonny," I would.
I thought about it.
But, I can't.
The kid doesn't listen
to shit I
-So is that a yes?
-Is it a yes?
Tio  ... Come on, man.
He's a good kid.
He's smart. He's funny.
He cares.
That kid does well in school,
he works hard.
And I could tell you.
I'm with him every day.
Working in my store.
I got that kid working to the
bone, but look, I'm...
He has an opportunity to have a
life that you and me didn't
Come on,  Tio.
How do you pay him?
Cash.
Ever wonder why?
Ever?
[door opens, closes]
-Perdón, Alejandro.
-Hey.
Thank you for letting me
come in
I was just wondering
about the status
We got good news,  mijo.
The check is cashed.
[chuckles]
[speaking Spanish]
[in English] So
there's no chance,
just to tie up some loose ends
before... before I go.
[speaking Spanish]
[in English] The place
is yours,  mijo.
Yeah, well...
You got cold feet?
No... No.
No, man.
I mean, that's amazing.
That's amazing.
Thank you again.
You know, just, life throws you
curve balls, but...
I'll figure it out. Thank you
again.
[speaking Spanish]
-[in English]
A dream come true, right?
[light piano playing]
[door closes]
[indistinct chatter]
So... Sonny's dad is okay with
him leaving?
Yeah... he's fine with it.
That's great.
Pero  you wore your  papi's  hat?
Yeah. It fits.
[speaking Spanish]
-[in English] Okay, okay.
-Okay?  Gracias, mi amor.
-Abuela.
-[speaking Spanish]
-Hey.
[in English] I want
to talk to you.
Oh, yeah. Okay.
-[doorbell buzzes]
-It's open.  Está abierto!
[all cheering]
Oh, we're in trouble now.
-How cute!
-Oh, my God, I love that dress.
I love your dress.
[excited clamoring]
Yo, look at this.
Good luck.
You're gonna need it.
Hey.
-What?
-[chuckles nervously]
I'm sorry, you just--
You look amazing.
-Thanks.
-My favorite color.
Well, I...
have a date tonight, so...
Word.
Right. That's right.
You have a date.
-I have a date, too.
-Oh, you do?
We. We have a date.
We have a date.
This is a date.
Let me get you a drink.
-[bottles clinking]
-Think fast.
All right, let's clean this up
before Abuela gets here.
[indistinct chatter]
Usnavi, Vanessa.  Ven, baila.
♪  No te vayas♪
-  ♪  Si me dejas♪
-No, not this song again!
♪  Si te alejas♪
♪  De mi♪
♪  Seguirás en mis recuerdos♪
[record skipping]
♪  Para siempre--
♪  Para siempre--♪
That scratch on the record is
her favorite part.
♪  Para siempre--♪
-The scratch on the record
is my favorite part.
[record skips]
[exclaiming]
Wow.
[in English] You don't want any
of it? Oh, yeah, you're trying
Let me give you
a vegan  pastel.
[speaking Spanish]
[in English] Nina!
You got sauce on my sleeve!
Tsk.
Pass me a tissue or something.
No, I got you.
-You're good.
-Wow.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
-Mirenlo.
-Now you know.
-Be generous.
-Yeah, we're gonna get it out.
-Wow.
-You know what I'm sayin'.
[speaking Spanish]
[in English] Nice.
I take note.
[speaking Spanish]
[in English] You know,
my first business,
You know what?
Every time you tell the story,
you're a different age, and you
get younger
-and younger and younger.
-I was seven or eight...
I took a rag and a coffee can,
I went to the  plaza  in Arecibo
to shine shoes for a nickel.
But every nickel went to shoe
polish, right?
Because the next time I could
charge a dime.
-Wow, my man was a hustler.
-'Cause you got that investment
-Hey, Benny!
-Hey, yo!
-The party's just starting,
siéntate.
-Let me make you a plate.
-No, no, I'm not hungry.
Benny, not hungry?
[speaking Spanish]
[in English] Yo, Kevin, that
meeting I walked in on with you
Is that what I thought it was?
'Cause, you know,
I keep playing
Adios.  I was saving that
news for dessert.
What news?
You know, when Pike originally
approached me, he wanted the
So today, I reopened the
conversation.
[speaking Spanish]
-[in English] What?
-I knew it.
I guess we're gonna
do this now,
[taps glass]
Nina... it was about your age
that your mother and I,
God rest her soul, we came here
and we emptied our savings to
put a down payment
Two burgundy Cadillacs,
that was
Start small, dream big.
I look at you,  mija,
I see her.
Y te lo juro  , if she were
here, she would've done the
Dad...
I sold Rosario's.
-  Felicidades!
-What?
-Raise a glass.
-  Felicidades!
-[speaking Spanish]
-[in English] Yes,
To Nina, who can now finish
what she started at Stanford.
To Nina!
-To Nina.
Nina, say, "Thank you,  Papi."
Dad... the deadline passed.
-I don't know what you're
talking about.
Stop with the lying. I called
them.
I called them!
Stop trying to protect me here.
There were other things other
than the finances.
Did you not hear what I said?
Yes, about the ignorant
idiotas  --
That's the same thing that
we foresaw when we came!
-No, it's not the same thing,
Dad.
[in English] It is not
the same.
When you came here and Mom came
here, you all had a Latino
ready to welcome you,
open arms,
and teachers and lawyers,
first generation,
There's no community for me at
school.
I got searched.
Yeah.
On moving day...
my roommate lost
her pearl necklace and...
the RA and her parents
came in...
and searched me and they...
emptied my drawers,
turned over my purse...
and I just stood there.
I stood there
and didn't say anything.
And then eventually,
they found it... in her bag.
You're the best
we've got, Nina.
If you can't stay in the ring,
what's that gonna say about us?
You can't keep
putting your life's work
Dile, mi gente,
isn't she the best we got?
And then I apologize
like an idiot.
I stood there,
I didn't do anything,
and then I apologized.
Well, you keep
getting A's, baby,
that's your revenge.
-My God, you're not
hearing her, Kevin.
-Como?
-I'm not going back!
So all of my decisions
can just go to hell here?
-I'm doing this for you!
-No, you're doing it for you!
What if I refuse your money?
What if I don't want it?
[speaking Spanish]
[in English] I refuse.
[door slams]
She refused.
Okay,  se acabo todo.  Get out!
[playing upbeat music]
Fiesta in the Heights!
[club people]
♪ Vanessa! ♪
♪ Damn, this is nice
I really like what
♪ So, the hot club
in Washington Heights ♪
♪ You might be right
This music's tight ♪
♪ Yo, did I mention
that you look great tonight ♪
-♪ Because you do
You really-- ♪
-Relax,  que relaxed?
I'm relaxed.
♪ So you've been here before ♪
♪ I don't go out
I get so busy with the store ♪
♪ Y cada dia
It's a brand new chore ♪
♪ My arms are sore
No time for the dance floor ♪
♪ But maybe you and me should
Hang out some more ♪
-♪ I'm such a dork, but I-- ♪
-♪ Let's go get a drink ♪
-♪ Something sweet ♪
-♪ You know me ♪
-♪ A little bit of cinnamon ♪
-♪ Wepa, Vanessa! ♪
Celebrate!
-♪ Here's to getting fired ♪
-♪ To killing the mood ♪
[both]
♪ Salud! ♪
-♪ Without so much
as a thank you ♪
[both]
♪ Cheers! ♪
♪ To finally getting Vanessa ♪
-♪ Boy, fix your collar ♪
-♪ Holler! ♪
♪ To doing shots
On the weekend ♪
♪ As long as you buy 'em
L'chaim! ♪
-♪ Hey you ♪
-♪ Who? ♪
-♪ You ♪
-♪ Who, me? ♪
-♪ You wanna dance? ♪
-♪ Naw, man ♪
♪ Okay, I took my chance ♪
♪ It's cool, it's cool
Hey, if you want to ♪
-♪ You don't mind? ♪
-♪ I'm fine, I'm fine ♪
-♪ Yo ♪
-♪ Who's Vanessa talkin' to? ♪
-♪ Some dude ♪
[Benny]
♪ Some dude? ♪
♪ That's messed up
She's tryin' to
♪ Jealous? I ain't jealous
I can take
[crowd cheering] Hey!
Oh, shit!
[club guys]  ♪ Vanessa, let me
Get the next one ♪
♪ Vanessa, let me
Interject some ♪
♪ The way you sweat
The way you flex on the floor ♪
♪ It makes me want you more ♪
♪ Vanessa, let me
Get the next one ♪
Interject some ♪
♪ The way you sweat
The way you flex on the floor ♪
♪ It makes me want you more ♪
♪ Vanessa, let me
Get the next one ♪
Interject some ♪
♪ The way you sweat
The way you flex on the floor ♪
♪ It makes me want you more ♪
♪ Bartender!
Let me get an amaretto sour
♪ How are you so pretty?
You complete me ♪
♪ You had me at "hello"
You know you need me ♪
♪ Truly, madly, deeply
Let's get freaky ♪
♪ Oh, I get it you're
The strong and silent type ♪
♪ Well, I'm the
Caribbean island type ♪
♪ And I can drive you wild
All night ♪
♪ But I digress
Say something
♪ No hablo ingles ♪
♪ Yes! ♪
[crowd cheering]
[crowd gasps]
[crowd cheers]
-  [speaking Spanish]
-[in English] Where you been?
-Yo, you been
doing your thing all night!
Yeah, hold up.
Wait, wait. Let's take a shot.
-You want a shot?
-No, it's fine.
Let me get you a shot.
-I'll be right back,
I'll be right back!
Two shots, please! Same thing.
[music stops]
-[crowd gasps]
-[glass breaking]
[crowd clamoring]
-♪ Oye, que paso? ♪
-♪ Blackout, blackout! ♪
♪ Vino el apagón
Ay, Dios! ♪
-♪ Oye, que paso? ♪
-♪ Blackout! Blackout! ♪
♪ Vino el apagón
Ay, Dios! ♪
♪ We are powerless ♪
♪ We are powerless,
We are powerless ♪
♪ Somebody better open
These goddamn doors ♪
-♪ Somebody better open
these goddamn doors ♪
-♪ We are powerless ♪
-I can't find Usnavi! ♪
-♪ Vanessa! ♪
-♪ Nina, where'd you go? ♪
-♪ Has anyone seen Benny? ♪
-♪ Benny! ♪
-♪ Nina, where'd you go? ♪
-♪ I can't find you! ♪
-♪ Usnavi! ♪
♪ It's hotter in the street
Everybody is nervous ♪
♪ Hey, yo, we gotta be Usnavi
Streetlights out of service ♪
♪ Because we're powerless
Our hour is at hand ♪
-♪ It's you and me ♪
-♪ You know what we gotta do? ♪
♪ Illuminate the community ♪
♪ When the sparks ignite
We gon' light up the night ♪
♪ Bottle rockets loco locus
Everybody, let's focus ♪
♪ Gather 'round, these are free
Grab your ammo and stack up ♪
♪ Give me a light
Till the power comes ♪
♪ Back up, back up, back up! ♪
♪ Look at the fireworks ♪
♪ Look at the fireworks fly ♪
♪ Light up the night sky ♪
♪ Look at the fireworks ♪
♪ Look at the fireworks fly ♪
♪ Light up the night sky ♪
-When was the last time
you saw her?
-Did she text you?
Did she call you?
I called her twice
and I texted her.
-She not hittin' me back.
-Get out of my car!
I gotta get
to the dispatch, man.
Yo, I gotta wait
for Vanessa, man.
-What are you talking about?
-Look, I might not
but I still
got one tonight, Nina.
Let it go.
I can't.
Just stick with Usnavi.
I'll see you later, all right?
-♪ We are powerless,
we are powerless ♪
♪ The crowd was manic ♪
♪ With everybody screaming
And shoving and shouting
-♪ And everyone's frantic! ♪
-♪ Aqui hay gente pero
-♪ Usnavi! ♪
-♪ Yeah! ♪
♪ Vanessa! ♪
-♪ You abandoned me ♪
-♪ Yo, what are
♪ Usnavi, all night
You barely even
♪ Don't make me laugh
I've been trying all night ♪
♪ You've been shaking your ass
With like half of the Heights ♪
-♪ Real nice ♪
-♪ You barely gave me
-♪ What? ♪
-♪ Do I get another dance? ♪
-♪ I'm leaving ♪
-♪ Vanessa ♪
♪ I gotta go ♪
♪ Don't walk away
from us tonight ♪
♪ I don't need
Anything tonight ♪
♪ I can find my way home ♪
-♪ Keep running away
From home ♪
♪ Without you ♪
♪ Look at the fireworks ♪
♪ Look at the fireworks fly ♪
♪ Light up the night sky ♪
♪ Look at the fireworks
Look at the fireworks fly ♪
♪ Light up the night sky ♪
[Benny] Nagle at Broadway,
I got a woman in labor,
she needs to go to
Columbia Presbyterian Hospital.
Can you get her there?
Thank you and happy birthday.
Yo, Kevin, I, um... I routed
all the incoming calls
-and I got the generator
covering the outgoing.
[speaking Spanish]
You smart.
-You so smart.
-[Cuca] Hi, baby.
You got here mad quick.
What's going on?
[speaking Spanish]
[in English] Yeah, long night
at the club.
[Daniela] Usnavi, what's wrong?
-Forget about it.
-Have a drink.
Toast to drama.
[indistinct chattering]
[Daniela]  Ay,
but you're too comfortable.
-[in English] G-51.
-Bingo, mother-lovers!
[chorus]
♪ Look at the fireworks ♪
♪ Abuela, are you all right? ♪
[chorus]
♪ Light up the night sky ♪
♪ The stars are out tonight! ♪
[chorus]
♪ Look at the fireworks ♪
♪ You're not alone tonight ♪
[chorus]
♪ Light up the night sky ♪
[both]
♪ You're not alone tonight ♪
Atención,
if you don't have a fare,
...at the synagogue
and head up to Regiment.
So if you're
crossing the bridge,
-pick up multiple riders.
-Go up to Dyckman, then.
Do what you gotta do.
I'll get you some water
in a minute.
All right. Put your feet up.
-That's better.
-All right.
-Ooh. That's better.
-You okay?
-Yes, thank you.
-All right.
[people cheering]
♪ Look at the fireworks
Look at the fireworks ♪
♪ Light up the night sky ♪
♪ In Washington... ♪
♪ Look at the fireworks ♪
♪ Light up the night sky ♪
-[Usnavi] I'm done. I'm done.
-[Cuca] Are we touching
Oh, my God. The fear!
[Abuela Claudia]
♪ Calor, calor ♪
♪ Calor ♪
♪ Ay, Mama ♪
♪ The summer's hottest day ♪
♪ Paciencia y fe ♪
♪ It was hotter at home
In La Vibora ♪
♪ The Washington Heights
Of Havana ♪
♪ A crowded city of faces
The same as mine ♪
♪ Back as a child
In La Vibora ♪
♪ I chased the birds
In the plaza ♪
♪ Praying, Mama
You would find work ♪
♪ Combing the stars
In the sky ♪
♪ For some sort of sign ♪
♪ Ay, Mama ♪
♪ So many stars in Cuba ♪
♪ En Nueva York we can't see
Beyond our streetlights! ♪
♪ To reach the roof
You gotta bribe the supa ♪
♪ Ain't no Cassiopeia
In Washington Heights ♪
♪ But ain't no food
En La Vibora ♪
♪ I remember nights
Anger in the streets ♪
♪ Hunger at the windows ♪
♪ Women folding clothes
Playing with my friends
♪ Mama needs a job
Mama says we're poor ♪
♪ One day you say
"Vamos a Nueva York" ♪
♪ And Nueva York was far
But Nueva York had work ♪
♪ And so we came ♪
♪ And now, I'm wide awake ♪
♪ A million years too late ♪
♪ I talk to you
Imagining what you'd do ♪
♪ Remembering what
We went through ♪
-♪ Nueva York! ♪
-♪ Ay, Mama! ♪
♪ It wasn't like today
You'd say ♪
♪ Paciencia y fe ♪
-♪ Paciencia y fe ♪
-♪ Paciencia y--
-♪ Fresh off the boat
♪ Freezing in early December ♪
♪ A crowded city in 1943 ♪
♪ Learning the ropes
In America ♪
♪ En español, I remember ♪
♪ Dancing with
Mayor La Guardia ♪
♪ All of society
Welcoming Mami and me ♪
[screams]
♪ You better clean this mess ♪
-♪ Paciencia y fe ♪
-♪ You better learn ingles ♪
-♪ Paciencia y fe
-♪ You better not be late ♪
♪ You better pull your weight ♪
♪ Are you better off
Than you were
♪ Sharing double beds
Trying to catch a break ♪
♪ Struggling with English ♪
♪ Listening to friends
Finally got a job
♪ So we cleaned some homes
Polishing with pride ♪
♪ Scrubbing the whole
Of the Upper East Side ♪
♪ The days into weeks
The weeks into years ♪
-♪ And here I stayed ♪
-♪ Paciencia y fe
♪ Paciencia y fe,
Paciencia y fe ♪
♪ And as I feed these birds ♪
♪ My hands begin to shake ♪
♪ And as I say these words ♪
♪ My heart's about to break ♪
-♪ And ay, Mama! ♪
♪ What do you do
When your dreams come true? ♪
-♪ And ay, Mama! ♪
-♪ I've spent my life ♪
♪ Inheriting dreams from you ♪
♪ I made it through
I survived ♪
♪ I did it ♪
♪ Now do I leave ♪
♪ Or stay? ♪
♪ All right, Mama ♪
♪ Okay ♪
♪ Paciencia y fe ♪
♪ Calor, calor ♪
♪ Calor ♪
Abuela.
Abuela, Abuela.
Daniela!
Abuela.
Call 911!
-Okay, okay, okay.
-[Usnavi] Call 911!
-Wait, what?
-[Daniela] I got you,
-[Carla] What's going on?
-No, no...
Daniela!
-[Carla] What's happening?
-[Usnavi] Bring her
Come here with some towels!
Okay, okay.
-It's gonna be okay.
-Abuela, it's gonna be okay.
I'm right here, Abuela,
I'm right here.
[siren wailing]
I'm right here, I'm right here.
♪ She was found
And pronounced... ♪
♪ At the scene
She was already lying in bed ♪
♪ Paramedics said
That her heart gave out ♪
♪ I mean, that's basically
What they said ♪
♪ They said
A combination of the stress
♪ Why she never
Took her medicine
♪ I like to think
She went out in peace ♪
♪ With pieces of bread crumbs
In her hand ♪
♪ Abuela Claudia
Had simple pleasures ♪
♪ She sang the praises
Of things we ignore ♪
♪ Glass Coke bottles,
Bread crumbs ♪
♪ A sky full of stars ♪
♪ She cherished these things ♪
♪ She'd say, "Alabanza" ♪
♪ Alabanza means
To raise this thing
♪ And to sing quite literally
"Praise to this" ♪
♪ When she was here
The path was clear ♪
♪ She was just here ♪
[Nina]
♪ Alabanza ♪
♪ Alabanza a doña
Claudia, Señor ♪
♪ Alabanza ♪
♪ Alabanza a
Doña Claudia, Señor ♪
♪ Alabanza ♪
[Nina and Kevin]
[all]  ♪ Alabanza a
Doña Claudia, Señor ♪
♪ Alabanza ♪
♪ Alabanza a
Doña Claudia, Señor ♪
♪ Alabanza ♪
♪ Alabanza a
Doña Claudia, Señor ♪
♪ Alabanza ♪
-♪ Paciencia y fe ♪
-♪ Alabanza ♪
-♪ Alabanza a
-♪ Paciencia y fe,
Doña Claudia ♪
♪ Alabanza ♪
Should we take a break?
No, Daddy, keep going.
[rattling outside]
[sighs]
[engine revving outside]
Hey, Pop.
Best days of my life.
It's creepy quiet.
Usually, the One Train's
up there, screeching.
Yo, I was thinking...
there's so much stuff going on.
And all it just got me thinking
about is, like... all the
And I just thought about you.
You're about
to change zip codes.
Country codes, actually.
Yeah, but
that's not till August.
I mean, you know, we got time.
Usnavi...
I'm the girl who paints nails.
There's plenty like me,
here and over there.
Stop!
Yo, you're an artist.
Yo, your senior year
lab book...
I should've been
paying attention
all them doodles you made.
Yo, it was like...
Wonder Woman  meets...
The Simpsons  meets...
Guernica.
-[Vanessa laughs]
-And I would...
I would watch, like...
I just want to see
the whole world
[Kevin chuckles]
Mira para allá.
Benny, you know,
before I bought Rosario's...
it was O'Hanrahan's.
The whole block was Irish.
[chuckles]
You know why I bought it?
My dad, he, uh... he pulled me
out of high school,
so that I could work on
the same farm as him.
Making the same pennies.
I thought to myself,
"No, no, no,  papi."
"That don't make no sense."
I'm gonna drop out
so somebody else
So I came here.
So I could make
my own damn work.
But, you never
finished high school?
But Nina did.
[Usnavi]  You asked me,
"What a  sueñito  means?"
I'm not gonna sit here
and give you
some fairy tale version.
You know, a dream isn't some
sparkly diamond we get.
You know, sometimes, it's...
it's rough.
And it's not so pretty.
-Yeah!
-  [speaking Spanish]
[in English] DACA was not
a gift from some benevolent
-No.
-No!
-[protest leader] You made
it happen, you fought for it.
[protest leader] And that's why
it still continues now.
'Cause what about the people
who don't qualify,
She gets into college
without papers, but...
no work-study for her,
no federal aid for her
so she doesn't
get to go to college.
-What did she say?
-She said her niece
[protest leader]
We can dream bigger
Yo, Sonny!
What's going on man?
[protest leader]
Let's do this. Yes!
I knew I couldn't
get a license.
But no college?
She was talking
about undocumented folks.
I remember when I was your age,
they used to say...
"If you work hard
and you live by the rules,
the money will come,
the things will come.
And that, those things
will complete you."
But, they won't.
We work so hard to try
and get there, that we forget
I was gonna be like you.
[protest leader
speaking Spanish]
Share your stories!
Share your stories.
There's nothing
[crowd chanting]
Tell our stories!
Dad, I know what I have to do.
You've given me
this amazing education
and figure out how
every undocumented kid
Maybe Stanford isn't a way out.
Maybe it's a way back.
Like Abuela
always used to say...
asserting our dignity
in small ways.
Wow.
This is it, huh,  mija?
What?
This is the moment
when you do better than me.
Not because of
some fancy degree...
It's 'cause you can
see a future that I can't.
Hey...
[in Spanish]
[in English] You're  Nuyoricua.
We're a people on the move,
so yeah, bring us with you.
Ignore anyone who doubts you.
You take all the bruises, baby,
but you stay in the ring.
[Usnavi]  I called,
and it's still available.
But Vanessa needs a co-signer,
and not one who's about
Would you?
As a personal favor?
We're all ready, ma'am.
That's  señorita  to you.
Yes. Yes, ma'am--
Señorita.  Yes.
Listas.  We'll follow behind.
-It's hotter in here.
-Put on the AC.
[both speaking Spanish]
Come find me in the Bronx.
3843 Grand Concourse.
Where the hell is everybody?
Diablo.  It's like
they've given up.
Bye, people!
Bye!
Carajo.
Ungrateful!
Our matriarch bites the dust,
and this is how we move on?
We are not power-less.
We are powerful.
If Claudia was here,
she'd say,  "P'alante."
In Puerto Rico,
blackouts happen all the time,
This is like
Gilligan's Ghetto Island.
Mi amor, cálmate,  huh?
What would Jesus do?
Do I look like Jesus to you?
-[Carla] I mean,
sometimes when I squint.
♪ Hey! ♪
♪ What's this tontería
That I'm seeing
♪ I never thought
I'd see the day ♪
♪ Since when are Latin people
Scared of heat? ♪
♪ When I was a little girl
Growing up in the hills
♪ My favorite time of year
Was Christmas time ♪
-♪ Ask me why ♪
-♪ Why? ♪
♪ There wasn't
An ounce of snow ♪
♪ But oh,
The coquito would flow ♪
♪ As we sang the aguinaldo
The carnaval
♪ Business is closed
And we're about to go ♪
♪ Let's have a carnaval ♪
♪ Del barrio ♪
♪ Wepa! ♪
♪ Carnaval del barrio ♪
♪ We don't need electricidad!
Get off your butt, avanza! ♪
♪ Saca la maraca,
Bring your tambourine
♪ Carnaval del barrio ♪
♪ Me, me, me!
Dani, I have a question ♪
♪ I don't know
What you're cantando ♪
♪ Just make it up as you go
We are improvisando ♪
♪ Lai, le, lo, lai,
Lo, le, lo, lai ♪
-♪ You can sing anything ♪
-Wait, what?
♪ Carla, whatever pops
Into your head
♪ Uh, my mom is Dominican-Cuban
My dad is from Chile
♪ I'm Chile-Domini-Curican... ♪
♪ But I always say
I'm from Queens ♪
♪ Carnaval del barrio ♪
♪ Why is everyone so happy?
We're sweating
♪ I gotta get out of here soon
This block's getting worse
♪ You can't even go to a club
With a friend ♪
♪ Without having somebody
Shove you ♪
♪ Ay, por favor! ♪
♪ Vanessa, don't pretend
That Usnavi's your "friend" ♪
♪ We all know
That he love you ♪
Wow.
♪ Now that you mention
That sexual tension
-♪ Yo, this is bogus ♪
-♪ Haven't you noticed ♪
♪ You get all your coffee
For free ♪
♪ Carnaval del barrio ♪
Here comes Usnavi!
♪ Yo! Yo! Yo, y-y-yo-yo ♪
♪ Now, now,
Everyone gather 'round ♪
♪ Sit down, listen,
I got an announcement ♪
♪ Wow, there's nothing here
Holding me down ♪
♪ The word is out
Tell the whole town
♪ Atención, I'm closin' shop
Sonny, grab everybody
♪ Twist off the bottle
Kiss it up to God ♪
♪ I miss Abuela Claudia
It's time to fly, though ♪
♪ Daniela, Carla,
pack up the carro ♪
♪ I'm booking a flight
For DR tomorrow! ♪
[all]  ♪ Oh, my God! ♪
♪ Alza la bandera
La bandera dominicana ♪
La bandera puertorriqueña ♪
♪ Alza la bandera
La bandera mexicana ♪
La bandera cubana ♪
-♪ P'arriba esa bandera! ♪
-♪ Hey! ♪
-♪ Alzala donde quiera! ♪
♪ Recuerdo de mi tierra ♪
♪ Me acuerdo de mi tierra ♪
-♪ Esa bonita bandera! ♪
-♪ Hey! ♪
-♪ Contiene mi alma entera! ♪
♪ Y cuando yo me muera ♪
♪ Entiérrame en mi tierra ♪
[piraguero vocalizing]
[all]
Hey!
♪ Hey, Mr. Benny
Have you seen
♪ What do you mean? ♪
♪ I heard you and Nina
Went for a roll in the hay! ♪
♪ Hey! Oh ♪
-♪ Benny and Nina,
Sitting in a tree ♪
-♪ K-I-S-S-I-N-G ♪
-It's your fault.
♪ Que bochinche
Nina and Benny ♪
-♪ K-I-S-S-I-N-G ♪
-Okay, okay.
♪ Hold up, wait a minute ♪
♪ Usnavi's leavin' us
For the Dominican Republic ♪
♪ And Benny went
And stole the girl
♪ She was
My babysitter first! ♪
♪ Listen up,
Is this what y'all want? ♪
♪ We close the bodega
The neighborhood is gone ♪
♪ They selling the dispatch
And they closin' the salon ♪
♪ And they'll never turn
The lights back on ♪
♪ 'Cause we are powerless
We are powerless ♪
♪ And y'all keep dancin'
And singin' and celebratin' ♪
♪ And it's gettin' late
And this place disintegratin' ♪
♪ We are powerless
We are powerless ♪
♪ All right, we're powerless
So light up a candle ♪
♪ There's nothing going on here
That we can't handle! ♪
♪ Maybe you're right, Sonny
Call in the coroners ♪
♪ Maybe we're powerless
A corner full of foreigners ♪
♪ Maybe this neighborhood's
Changing forever ♪
♪ Maybe tonight
Is our last night together
♪ How do you want to face it? ♪
♪ Do you wanna waste it
When the end is so close
♪ Y'all could cry
With your head in the sand ♪
♪ I'mma fly this flag
That I got in my hand ♪
-♪ P'arriba esa bandera! ♪
-♪ Hey! ♪
-♪ Alzala donde quiera! ♪
♪ Can we raise
Our voice tonight? ♪
-♪ Can we make
A little noise tonight? ♪
♪ Esa bonita bandera
Contiene mi alma entera ♪
♪ In fact
Can we sing so loud
♪ They can hear us
Across the bridge
♪ P'arriba esa bandera ♪
♪ Alzala donde quiera ♪
♪ From Puerto Rico
To Santo Domingo ♪
♪ Wherever we go
We rep our people
♪ Esa bonita bandera ♪
♪ Contiene mi alma entera ♪
♪ Vanessa, forget about
What coulda been ♪
♪ Dance with me one last night
In the hood again ♪
♪ Wepa! ♪
♪ Carnaval del barrio ♪
♪ P'arriba esa bandera ♪
♪ Y cuando yo me muera ♪
-♪ Carnaval del barrio ♪
-♪ Entiérrame en mi tierra ♪
-♪ Del barrio ♪
-♪ Alza la bandera♪
♪ La bandera dominicana ♪
-♪ Alza la bandera ♪
♪ La bandera puertorriqueña ♪
-♪ Alza la bandera,
la bandera mexicana ♪
♪ Alza la bandera
La bandera ♪
♪ La bandera, la bandera,
la bandera ♪
♪ Alza la bandera, hey! ♪
[all cheering]
[Carla] We love you!
We love you! Bye!
[Benny] All right.
Watch your hand, move--
-[Nina] Okay, okay, okay...
Got it...
-My finger!
-Oh, my gosh. Yo.
Listen, I got this.
Just push. Just push down.
Oh, my gosh.
Ooh!
Oh, my gosh. You're only
gone to Thanksgiving.
Nina.
Let me just listen to my block.
Sunset looked better
in the blackout.
Well, how about...
...we pretend
we're still in it?
-I like that.
-Yeah?
Early July...
The whole summer
is ahead of us.
[laughs]
♪ When the sun goes down ♪
♪ You're gonna
Need a flashlight ♪
♪ You're gonna need a candle ♪
♪ I think I can handle that ♪
[chuckles]
♪ When you leave town ♪
♪ I'm gonna buy you
A calling card ♪
[chuckles]
-♪ 'Cuz I'm falling hard
For you ♪
♪ I go back on Labor Day ♪
♪ And I will try
To make my way ♪
♪ Out west to California ♪
♪ So we've got the summer ♪
♪ And we've got each other ♪
♪ Perhaps even longer ♪
♪ When you're on your own ♪
♪ And suddenly without me ♪
♪ Will you forget about me? ♪
♪ I couldn't if I tried ♪
♪ When I'm all alone ♪
♪ And I close my eyes ♪
[both]  ♪ That's when
I'll see your face again ♪
♪ And when you're gone ♪
♪ You know that
I'll be waiting ♪
♪ When you're gone ♪
♪ But you're here with me ♪
-♪ Right now ♪
-♪ We'll be working hard ♪
♪ But if we should
Drift apart ♪
-♪ Benny ♪
-♪ Let me take this moment ♪
-♪ Just to say ♪
-♪ No, no ♪
♪ You are gonna
Change the world some day ♪
♪ I'll be thinking of home ♪
♪ And I'll think of you
Every night ♪
♪ At the same time ♪
♪ When the sun goes down ♪
Nina didn't even let them
drive her to the airport.
She had to take that step
on her own.
An independent, stubborn lady.
Like you,  hija.
And that's good.
[grunts]
[exhales]
[sighs]
What?
No, you didn't!
No, you did not!
Yo, you playing tricks on me!
Yo, you playing tricks
on me, man!
Yo, Abuela...
[sighs]
[chuckles]
Hello? Yes, what time
do you close?
Word! Yes!
Okay, thank you so much.
Thank you, bye.
Whoa!
Hi!
-Were you just
standing there, just...
I... I heard you
fly out tomorrow.
Yeah.
-Yo, come in, come in, come in.
-Thanks.
Yeah.
[breathing heavily]
So how's the new spot?
It's great.
[sighs] My fingers won't budge.
I haven't sewn a single thing
-You will.
-Yeah.
Just... waiting for inspiration
to strike, I guess.
Well, you're pretty creative
and artistic, I mean...
-So... it's gonna hit you,
I think.
♪ So... ♪
♪ I got you a present ♪
♪ I went next door to get it ♪
♪ Doing anything tonight? ♪
-♪ Cleaning ♪
-♪ You're done for the day ♪
-♪ No way ♪
-♪ 'Cuz we got a date ♪
♪ Okay ♪
♪ Before you board that plane ♪
♪ I owe you a bottle
Of cold champagne ♪
-♪ No ♪
-♪ Yeah, cold champagne ♪
♪ Damn, the bottle's
All sweaty and everything ♪
♪ You went and got this ♪
-♪ Pop the champagne ♪
-♪ I don't know
♪ Or plastic cups
I already packed the cups ♪
♪ Tonight we're drinking
Straight from the bottle ♪
-♪ Usnavi ♪
-♪ Yeah ♪
♪ Daniela told me
What you did for me ♪
♪ And it's honestly
The sweetest thing
♪ Now, what can I say or do
To possibly repay you
♪ How do you get
This gold shit off? ♪
-♪ Usnavi ♪
-♪ Yeah ♪
♪ Before you go leave town ♪
♪ Before the corner changes
And the signs are taken down ♪
♪ Let's walk around
the neighborhood
-♪ Usnavi, are you all right? ♪
-♪ I'm fine ♪
♪ I'm trying
To open this champagne ♪
♪ You see the twisty thing
Is broken ♪
♪ But I'm gonna
Open this damn champagne ♪
-♪ Let me see it ♪
-♪ No, I got it ♪
♪ Yo, Usnavi,
drop the champagne ♪
♪ I mean you went
To all this trouble
♪ And it's gonna be okay ♪
♪ I'm sorry,
It's been a long day ♪
-♪ You oughta stay ♪
-♪ What? ♪
♪ You could stay uptown
Maybe save this place ♪
♪ Ha, ha, very funny ♪
♪ And it's not like
Sonny's got role models ♪
-♪ Role models? ♪
-♪ Stepping up to the plate ♪
-♪ Yo, what are
you talking about? ♪
♪ I think your vacation
Can wait ♪
♪ Vacation?
Vanessa, you left us too ♪
♪ And I moved down to
West Fourth Street ♪
-♪ You can take the A ♪
-♪ What are you
♪ You're leaving the country ♪
♪ And we're never
Gonna see you again ♪
♪ So what are
You trying to say? ♪
♪ You get everyone
Addicted to your coffee
♪ Vanessa, I don't know
Why you're mad at me ♪
♪ I wish I was mad ♪
♪ I'm just too late ♪
[door opens]
[door closes]
[Usnavi] How long
does this process take?
[Alejandro] Well,
from the original
appearances, appeals,
to a final decision...
could be five months.
Or five years.
-[Usnavi] Five years?
-[Alejandro] Yeah.
For a green card
or a rejection.
See, the courts work
at their own speed.
[Usnavi] Then we start today.
This is worth 96,000.
How much fight
does this buy us?
I wanna pay for your fee,
and the rest put
-Dude.
-It don't matter.
Holy shit,
that's a lot of money.
-Watch your mouth, bro.
-When did you get that?
What you mean,
when did I get it? Don't worry
Why you always
asking questions?
You know, payment in checks
is more common.
I leave on the first flight
in the morning.
I don't have time
to cash in now.
I wish I did, but I like--
Please.
All right.
Bueno, mijo...
...this is gonna be
an emotional rollercoaster.
It may end in heartbreak.
-But, there's a chance, right?
-Yeah.
But it's my responsibility
to make sure that he knows...
the odds are against you.
[Sonny] Understood.
I still want to fight, though.
[Alejandro] Okay.
[spray paint can rattling]
[spray painting]
Pete!
Seriously?
My bad. Use one of those rags.
Hey...
How much for this?
Free. I got tons like that.
You hear that?
The voices of the gods.
My last morning,
the One Train...
sounded like Juan Luis Guerra.
And the garbage trucks
smelled like island flowers.
Best days of my life.
Here I come.
[bolero singer]
♪ No te vayas ♪
♪ Si me dejas ♪
♪ Si te alejas ♪
♪ De mi ♪
♪ Seguirás en mis recuerdos ♪
♪ Para siempre-- ♪
♪ Para siempre--
Para siempre-- ♪
♪ Para siem--
Para siem-- ♪
-♪ Para siempre ♪
-[Usnavi]  ♪ Lights out on
♪ And now the crack of dawn ♪
♪ I pack as life goes on
And on and on ♪
♪ Time to go,
But I'm doing the math ♪
♪ On this cash money
To have Sonny
♪ Abuela really wanted me
Up on a beach
♪ And soon that's
How it's gonna be ♪
♪ And look at me,
Leavin' today ♪
♪ On a 747 boardin' JFK ♪
[Carla]
♪ The hydrants are open ♪
♪ Cool breezes blow ♪
[Daniela, Carla and Cuca]
♪ The hydrants are open ♪
♪ Cool breezes blow ♪
-[Kevin]  ♪ Good morning ♪
-[piraguero]
-[Daniela, Carla and Cuca]
♪ Cool breezes ♪
-♪ Blow ♪
-♪ So sweet and nice, piragua ♪
♪ Piragua, piragua ♪
-♪ The hydrants are open ♪
-♪ Piragua, piragua ♪
-♪ Cool breezes ♪
-♪ New block of ice, piragua ♪
-♪ Blow ♪
-♪ So sweet and nice, piragua ♪
♪ Piragua, piragua ♪
-♪ Siempre ♪
-♪ The hydrants are open ♪
-♪ Cool breezes ♪
-♪ New block of ice, piragua ♪
-♪ Blow ♪
-♪ So sweet and nice, piragua ♪
♪ It won't be long now ♪
♪ There's a breeze
Off the Hudson
♪ You think
You're sick of living here
♪ The morning light
Off the fire escapes ♪
♪ The nights in Bennett Park
Blasting Big Pun tapes ♪
♪ I'mma miss this place
To tell you the truth ♪
♪ Kevin dispensin' wisdom
From his dispatch booth ♪
♪ And at dawn
Vanessa at the salon ♪
♪ We gotta move on
But who's gonna notice
♪ When our job's done ♪
♪ As the evening winds down
To a crawl, son ♪
♪ Can I ease my mind
When we're all done? ♪
♪ When we've resigned
In the long run
♪ Most of all,
I'll miss Abuela's whispers ♪
♪ Doin' the Lotto Pick Six
Every Christmas ♪
♪ In five years,
When this whole city's
♪ Who's gonna miss
This raggedy little business? ♪
Hey, you.
Hey.
Do you have two minutes?
Yeah.
You said you wanted
to see the world
-Yeah.
-Come with me.
-No peeking.
-All right.
-Okay.
Watch it.
-Where am I going?
-Just stand right here.
-Where?
-No peeking.
-I'm not--
-I can feel you trying
-I'm not trying--
-Just don't.
Hold on.
Okay, open.
After I left your place
last night, I just...
walked around for a while.
And then I ran into Pete.
And I saw one
of his drop cloths, and...
I thought that this
is my next piece.
So I called Sonny and I told
him to open up the bodega,
'cause my fingers
needed to move.
She started working
and was like,
So I started painting.
Yo, how did you...
That's my dad's beach.
Yeah. You had all those photos
by the register.
I worked from memory.
-I did the crab in the corner.
-[laughs]
What's so funny?
[Graffiti Pete] Who cares
about the crab in the corner?
[Sonny] What you mean,
the crab is like the best part.
[Graffiti Pete] No, it is not.
It's in the corner
[Sonny] So what, are you saying
you don't like my crab?
[Graffiti Pete] I may be saying
a lot of things,
that just looks like
a fourth-grader drew that.
-[Sonny] You could sell that.
-[Graffiti Pete] No, I cannot.
-25 cents?
-[Sonny] No,
[Graffiti Pete] What?
-Yeah.
-I'm saying... just...
-He hates it.
-[sighs]
[Sonny] He's forming
an artistic opinion.
♪ You did this last night? ♪
♪ Yeah ♪
♪ There goes my flight ♪
What?
♪ Graffiti Pete you're gonna
Need some new cans
-♪ There's been
A slight change of plans ♪
♪ Listen up guys, you got a job
I'm not playin' ♪
♪ You gotta go now
Tell the whole block
♪ So go ahead,
Tell everyone we know
♪ All right, go ♪
Yo! Usnavi's stayin'!
♪ Yeah, I'm a streetlight
Chillin' in the heat ♪
♪ I illuminate the stories
Of the people in the street ♪
♪ Some have happy endings
Some are bittersweet ♪
♪ But I know them all
And that's what
-Yeah!
-♪ And if not me,
♪ Who's gonna keep
The coffee sweet
♪ Abuela, rest in peace
You live in my memories ♪
♪ But Sonny's gotta eat
This corner is my destiny ♪
♪ Brings out the best in me
We pass a test
♪ And yes indeed
You know I'll never leave ♪
♪ If you close your eyes
That hydrant is a beach
♪ That fire escape's a leaf
On a palm tree ♪
♪ Abuela, I'm sorry
But I ain't goin' back
♪ Because I'm telling
Your story ♪
♪ And I can say goodbye
To you smilin'
♪ I been on it this whole time
I'm home ♪
Until then...
I thought it was past tense.
What?
The best days of my life.
So I stayed.
And I built my little dream,
my  sueñito,
here, in Washington Heights.
Say it,
so it doesn't disappear.
[kids] Washington Heights!
Because this place...
this is it.
You... you,  nena.
You're it.
Para siempre--
[Vanessa]
I have a date tonight.
[Usnavi]
I take note.
But, there's a chance, right?
[Sonny]  We sold... a winner!
[Kevin]
Start small, dream big.
[Abuela Claudia]
Little details...
that tell the world
we are not invisible.
Can we go to the water now?
Man, you've been
talking forever.
Yeah, come on, Iris.
Please, Daddy? Can I go, too?
Ask your mother.
Mami,  can I?
Please?
Yes,  mi vida,  go.
[kids] Yes!
Love you, Daddy.
[community]
♪ The hydrants are open ♪
♪ Cool breezes blow ♪
-♪ We're home ♪
-♪ The hydrants are open ♪
♪ Cool breezes blow ♪
♪ It's a wonderful life
That I've known ♪
♪ Merry Christmas you ol'
Building and Loan! ♪
-♪ I'm home ♪
-♪ The hydrants are open ♪
♪ Cool breezes blow ♪
♪ Abuela, that ain't a stoop
That's your throne ♪
♪ Long after your birds
Have all flown
♪ Where the coffee's non-stop
And I drop this hip-hop ♪
♪ In my mom and pop shop
I'm home ♪
♪ Where people come, people go
Let me show all of these people
♪ There's no place like home ♪
♪ And let me set
The record straight ♪
♪ I'm steppin' to Vanessa
I'm gettin' a second date ♪
♪ I'm home
Where it's 100 in the shade ♪
♪ But with patience and faith
We remain unafraid ♪
♪ I'm home ♪
♪ You hear that music
In the air? ♪
♪ Take the train
To the top of the world
♪ I'm home! ♪
["Home All Summer" playing]
[soft music playing]
♪ It's hotter than
The islands are today ♪
♪ And Mister Softee's truck
Has broken down ♪
Send somebody over here.
I don't--
♪ And here come
All his customers my way ♪
♪ I told you, I run this town ♪
♪ Piragua, piragua ♪
Ain't that some shit?
♪ $1.25, piragua ♪
♪ Piragua, piragua ♪
♪ Two twenty-five, piragua ♪
♪ New block of ice
Hike up the price ♪
♪ Lai, lo, le, lo, lai!
Lai, lo, le, lo, lai! ♪
♪ Blackouts on ice
Blackouts on ice ♪
♪ Lo, le, lo, lai!
Keep scraping by ♪
♪ Piragua! ♪